Guide to the Richard Courant Papers MC 150
New York University Archives
- Series II: Files from the Office of Richard Courant
  - Subseries A: General Files
    - Niro, Pio, 1948 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Nitsche, Johannes, 1963-1968 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Nobel Prize in Mathematics, 1966, undated (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Noble, Charles, 1938 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Noether Library, 1936-1938 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - NONR Contract 285 (44)--Correspondence, Proposals, Misc. Salaries [Office of Naval Research], 1958-1961 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Northwestern University Applied Mathematics Group, 1945 (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - "Note About My Plans", 1950, 1958 (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - "Note on the Present Administrative Crisis in NYU", 1951 (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Notre Dame, University of, 1964 (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Novosibirsk Meeting on Partial Differential Equations, Report on (1 of 2), 1963 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Novosibirsk Meeting on Partial Differential Equations, Report on (2 of 2), 1963 (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - Nowak, Amran, Associates, Inc. (see "Film--Mathematical Association of America"), 1966 (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - "O" Misc., 1950-1954 (Box 70, Folder 26)
    - "O" Misc., 1965-1971 (Box 70, Folder 27)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1954-1956 (Box 70, Folder 28)
    - Oakley, C.O., 1951-1954 (Box 70, Folder 29)
    - Oberlander, Gustav, 1936 (Box 70, Folder 30)
    - Oberwolfach Meeting, 1967 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - "Observations Concerning the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton", 1950 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Office of Naval Intelligence, 1946 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Office of Naval Research (see "U.S. Navy"), 1961-1967 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1943-1947 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Office of Scientific Research and Development Memos, 1942-1944 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Office of Scientific Research and Development Memos, 1944-1946 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Office of Technical Services, 1948 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Oleinik, Olga A. (see "Russian Mathematians"), 1962-1969 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - "On the Classification of Partial Differential Equations", undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - "On the Mathematics Curriculum of the High School" - The Mathematics Teacher, 1962 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - "One-Dimensional Progressing Waves" (incomplete), undated (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1939-1954 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1945-1950 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Oravas, Gunhard, 1963-1965 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Outline of Topics Covered in Theory of a Complex Variable (Excluding Chapter 1), undated (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Ovsyannikov, L.V., 1960-1962 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Oxford University Press, 1943-1960 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Oxford University Press, 1963-1970 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - "P" Misc., 1927-1960 (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - "P" Misc., 1961-1970 (Box 71, Folder 21)
    - Packard, B., 1966 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Palmer Physical Laboratory--Princeton, 1951-1953 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Panel Meeting, Remarks at Siam (1 of 2), 1961 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Panel Meeting, Remarks at Siam (2 of 2), 1961 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Parker, Frank, 1945-1955 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Parker, Frank (see also "Squid"), 1947-1950 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Parsegian, V.L., 1954 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Parsegian, V.L., 1961-1962 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Partial Differential Equations--lectures given by Courant, 1948-1949 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Partial Differential Equations--Watson seminar, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Peck, Leslie G., 1961 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Pekeris, C.L.--"Asymptotic Solutions for the Normal Modes in the Theory of Microwave Propagation", 1946 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Pekeris, C.L.--"Notes on the Scattering of Radiation in an Inhomogeneous Medium", 1947 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Pekeris, C.L.--"Theory of Propagation of Sound in a Half-Space of Variable Sound Velocity under Conditions of Formation of a Shadow Zone", 1946 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Penney, W.G., 1951 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Pennsylvania, University of, 1946 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Petrowsky, I., undated (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Physical Science Study Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Physik II, R. Courant und D. Hilbert [ Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II] -- Copy 4, chapters 1-3, 1937 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Physik II, R. Courant und D. Hilbert [ Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II] -- Copy 4, chapters 4-5, 1937 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Physik II, R. Courant und D. Hilbert [ Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II] -- Copy 4, chapter 6, 1937 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Physik II, R. Courant und D. Hilbert [ Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II] -- Copy 4, chapter 7 (pages missing), 1937 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Pick, Hilde, 1948-1961 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Pickett--Contracts, 1951 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Picone, Mauro, 1952-1959, undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Picone, Mauro, 1967 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Piel, G. (see "Scientific American"), undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Pinl, Max, 1947-1950 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Piore, E.R. (IBM), 1948-1949 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Piore, E.R. (IBM), 1961-1969 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Pirani, M., 1940-1941, undated (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Piza, Pedro, 1942-1949 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Pleijel, A., undated (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Pohle, Frederick, 1957 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Polya, George, 1937-1954 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1964-1969 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - Post Office, 1944 (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Prager, William, 1951-1966, undated (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Prandtl, L., 1948-1950 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Pratorius, Elisabeth (1 of 2), 1925-1927 (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - Pratorius, Elisabeth (2 of 2), 1925-1927 (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - Preface-- Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II, 1961 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - President's Science Advisory Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - President's Science Advisory Committee, 1960 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University, 1945-1948 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Princeton University, 1953-1957 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Princeton University Bicentennial (1 of 2), 1946 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Princeton University Bicentennial (2 of 2), 1946 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Printing--photo offset, 1944-1945 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - "Promotion of Scholarly Standards in the University, Concerning the", 1949 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - "Proposals Regarding an Institute for Basic Sciences", 1952 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Proposed Mathematics Institute--old correspondence, 1938-1953 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence from and regarding J.R. Kline
    - "Proposed Organization of the Institute of Mathematical Sciences at NYU" (Memorandum B), 1952 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Provisional International Computation Centre (1 of 2), 1951-1960 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Provisional International Computation Centre (2 of 2), 1951-1960 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Provisional International Computation Centre, 1961 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - (Courant) Publications in German, circa 1963 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Publications Misc.--"Energy Relations for General Hyperbolic Equations", undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Publications Misc.--"The Propagation of Discontinuities in Wave Motion" (with P.D. Lax), circa 1956 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Publication of Reports, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Publicity Trip--Russia, 1963 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Puschel, Werner--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1930 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - "Q" Misc., 1962 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - "R" Misc., 1936-1960 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Rabi, I.I., 1963-1965 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Rademacher, Hans, 1937-1970 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Rademacher, Hans, 1947-1955 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Hans Rademacher Instructorships, 1968-1969 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Radiation Laboratory--Livermore, 1953-1958 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Radiation Lab--MIT, 1942-1943 (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Rado, Tibor, 1940-1953 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Rado, Tibor, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Ramanathan, K.G., 1956, 1959, 1961 (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - Ramo-Wooldridge Corp., 1954-1960 (Box 75, Folder 18)
    - Rand Corporation, 1954-1955 (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - Rashevsky, Nicholas, 1954 (Box 75, Folder 20)
    - Raven Press, 1963-1965 (Box 75, Folder 21)
    - "Rechenmaschinen fur mathematische Probleme der Hydrodynamik und Reaktortechnik", undated (Box 75, Folder 22)
    - Reelle Funktionen, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Rees, Mina, 1943-1958 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Reid, W.T., 1938-1941 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Reidemeister, Kurt, 1947-1960 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Reissner, Eric--"Analysis of Shear Lag in Box Beams by the Principle of Minimum Potential Energy", 1946 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Reissner, Eric--"Buckling of Plates with Intermediate Rigid Supports", 1945 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Reissner, Eric--"Note on the Shear Stresses in a Bent Cantilever Beam of Rectangular Cross Section", 1946 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Reissner, Eric--"Solution of a Class of Singular Integral Equations", 1945 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Reissner, Eric--"Stresses and Small Displacement of Shallow Spherical Shells I, II", 1946-1947 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Relationship of the Computer Council to NYU Facility, Memorandum Concerning, 1953 April 23 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Relief and Research Fund, Inc. (Leo Wallerstein), 1953-1954 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Rellich, Franz (1 of 2), 1945-1957 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Rellich, Franz (2 of 2), 1945-1957 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Rellich, Franz, 1948-1955 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Rellich, Franz--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1930 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Remington Rand, 1953-1955 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Renner, D. & Barbara (and family), 1944-1961 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1966-1967 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Report to Chancellor Chase of the Evaluating Committee on the Institute for Mathematics and Mechanics in New York University, related correspondence, 1935-1946 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Reprints from ONERA, 1955-1969 (Box 76, Folder 20)
      Contains materials on MIT's Industrial Liaison Program, published works from various mathematicians 1962-1964
    - Reprint Requests, 1952, 1964-1967 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Republic Aviation Corporation, 1954-1955 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Research Board of National Security, 1945 (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - [Mathematical] Reviews, 1951-1952 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Richardson, R.G.D. [Brown University], 1937-1941 (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Richardson, R.G.D. [Brown University], 1943-1946 (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - Richter, Werner, 1938-1953 (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - Richtmeyer, Robert D., 1954-1960 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Richtmeyer, Robert D., 1961-1965 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Richtmeyer, Robert D.--Articles, 1959 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Riesser, Hans, 1952-1955 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Riesz, Marcel, 1954-1955 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Ritt, Joseph F., 1938-1950 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Ritter, Irving, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Robbins, Herbert, 1941-1960 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Roberts, E.S., 1946-1959 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Roberts, E.S.--Galley Proof-- Biology: The Key to the Riddle of Cancer, 1946-1959 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1951 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Rockefeller Fund Correspondence, 1945-1951 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Rohrl, Helmut, 1961-1962 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Roosevelt, George E., 1951-1961 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Rosbaud, Paul, 1951-1953 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Rose, Milton, 1955-1960 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Rose, Simon (and Marian), 1948-1960 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Rosenberg, Anna M., 1950-1954 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Rosenthal, Arthur, 1939-1955 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Roth, Sidney G., 1967 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Rothe, E.H., 1937-1939 (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Rothe, E.H.--"Completely Continuous Scalars and Variational Methods, 1948 (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Rothe, E.H.--"Gradient Mappings and Extrema in Banach Spaces", 1948 (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Rothstein, Luise, 1938-1943 (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Russian Mathematicians--Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Russian Mathematicians--Correspondence, 1965-1971 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Russian Scientists--Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Rutishauser, Heinz, 1948-1949 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - "Sa-Sm" Misc., 1947-1960 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - "Sn-Sz" Misc. (1 of 2), 1947-1959 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - "Sn-Sz" Misc. (2 of 2), 1947-1960 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - "S" Misc., 1943-1950 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - "S" Misc., 1951-1955 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - "S" Misc., 1961-1962, 1970-1971 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - "S" Misc., 1963-1968 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - "S" Misc., 1968-1969 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Sadowsky, Michael, 1937-1939 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Sargeant, Howland [Alien Property Custodian], 1941-1946 (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Sarton, George, 1942-1946 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Savage, L.J.--"The Application of Vectoral Methods of Metric Geometry", 1946 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Sawyer, W.W. (1 of 2), 1957 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Sawyer, W.W. (2 of 2), 1957 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Sawyer, W.W.--"An Introduction to Modern Algebra" (with Leon van Hove) (1 of 2), 1957 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Sawyer, W.W.--"An Introduction to Modern Algebra" (with Leon van Hove) (2 of 2), 1957 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Schafer, Richard D., 1953-1954 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Schaffeld, Egon, 1945-1956 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Schaffeld, Egon--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1924 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Schardin, Hubert, 1950-1958 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Schardin, Hubert--spare copies, memo and translation, letter, 1951 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Scherberg, Max, 1949-1950 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Schiffer, Menahem, 1947-1950 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Schild, A., 1957-1962 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Schimmel, H., 1945-1957 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Schmid, H.L., 1948-1957 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Schmidt, Arnold, 1947-1950 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Schmidt, F.K., 1947-1960 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Schoenberg, I., 1937-1945 (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Schumann, W.O., 1948 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Schwartz, Laurent, 1947-1950 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Schwartz, Laurent--lecture series given at Canadian Mathematical Congress, 1949 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Schwartz, Paul, 1949 (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - Schwerdtfeger, Hans, 1954-1958 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - Science Center at Washington Square, A Proposal for Support of (1 of 3), 1967 (Box 79, Folder 22)
    - Science Center at Washington Square, A Proposal for Support of (2 of 3), 1967 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Science Center at Washington Square, A Proposal for Support of (3 of 3), 1967 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Science Development Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Science Development Committee (1 of 2), 1967 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Science Development Committee (2 of 2), 1967 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Science Fair--Westchester [also includes Rockland County], 1961-1962 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Scientific American, 1964-1966 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Scientific American--Courant article, draft material (1 of 2), 1964 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Scientific American--Courant article, draft material (2 of 2), 1964 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Scientific Manpower, Memorandum on Training of, 1951 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Scientific Manpower, Memorandum Proposing a Plan to Relieve Shortage of, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - The Scientific Monthly, 1955-1956 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - "Scientific Rehabilitation in Europe and the Marshall Plan", 1948 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Scientists' Committee on Loyalty Problems, 1948-1950 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Scott, E.J., 1951 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Scripps Institution of Oceanography, 1946-1949 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Section T, 1945 (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Security, 1947-1948 (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Security Questionnaires, etc., 1952-1960 (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - Sedov, L.I.-- Dimensional and Similarity Methods in Mechanics Chapter I, 1957, undated (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - Sedov, L.I.-- Dimensional and Similarity Methods in Mechanics Chapter II, 1957 (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - Sedov, L.I.-- One-Dimensional Unsteady Gas Motion Chapter IV (1 of 3), undated (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Sedov, L.I.-- One-Dimensional Unsteady Gas Motion Chapter IV (2 of 3), undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Sedov, L.I.-- One-Dimensional Unsteady Gas Motion Chapter IV (3 of 3), undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Seeger, R.J. (1 of 2), 1944-1959 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Seeger, R.J. (2 of 2), 1944-1959 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Seeger, R.J.--"On Galileo and Statics", 1964 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Seeger, R.J.--"On Understanding Electric Breakdown in Solids", 1944 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Seeger, R.J.--"On Understanding Physical Phenomena", 1964 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Seeger, R.J.--"The Will to be Free", 1963 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Seidel, Wladimir, 1939-1945 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Selzer, Elchanan, 1947-1948 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Seminar, 1920-1921 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Seminar: Mathematical Problems Arising from Quantum Mechanics, 1950 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Service Bureau Corp. (subsidiary of IBM), 1959-1960 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Service Bureau Corp. (subsidiary of IBM), 1961-1962 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Seynsche, Ingeborg--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1929 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Shapely, Harlow, 1941-1948 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Shaw, Robert, 1944-1950 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Shaw, Robert, 1951-1955 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Shevlin, R., 1961 (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - Shiffman, Max, 1961-1967 (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - Shiffman, Max and Bella, 1951-1966 (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - Shiffman, Max--Lectures on Calculus of Variations (1 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Shiffman, Max--Lectures on Calculus of Variations (2 of 2), 1947-1948 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Shock Tube Symposium, 7th International--Canada, 1969 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Siberian Mathematical Journal, 1966-1967 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Siegel, Carl, 1947-1950 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Siegel, Carl--"Analytic Functions of Several Complex Variables", 1948 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Siegel, Carl--"Analytic Functions of Several Complex Variables", 1948 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Siegel, Carl--"Lectures on Analytic Number Theory" (1 of 2), 1945 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Siegel, Carl--"Lectures on Analytic Number Theory" (2 of 2), 1945 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Siegel--Manuscript, undated (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Siemiankowski, Feliks, 1960-1961, undated (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Signature, Unofficial Bio, Requests, etc., 1966-1970, undated (Box 82, Folder 12)
      Contains requests for autographs, fan letters
    - Simon, Herman E.--Riegelman, Strasser, Schwarz and Spiegelberg, 1947-1953 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1959-1960, 1967 (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1960-1966 (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Sloan Foundation, undated (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Sloan Foundation, undated (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Smith, Paul, 1949-1957 (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - Soap Film Experiments, 1941-1959 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Society for Ethical Culture, 1966-1967 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics, 1961-1963 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics, 1964-1965 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics, 1966-1967 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Sokolnikoff, I.S., 1944-1949 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Solomon, Alan, 1963-1970 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Spath, Hans--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1927 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Sperber, Elfriede and Hans, 1947-1951 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Sperry Gyroscope, 1944 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Springer, Ferdinand, 1938-1950 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Springer, Ferdinand, 1951-1955 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Springer, Georg, 1951-1959 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Springer-Verlag, 1938-1961 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Springer-Verlag, 1953-1955 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Springer-Verlag, 1955-1959 (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Squid, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Squid, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Squid--Fiscal Survey, 1949-1951 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Squid--Policy Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - SRA (Scientific Research Associates), 1966-1967 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - SRG (Statistical Research Group--Columbia University)--Personnel, 1945 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Stanford University, 1966, 1970 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Statement Concerning Structure of IMS and AEC Computing and Applied Mathematics Center, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Statistical Statement (IMS), 1958 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Stecher, Arne Helge, undated (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Stein, Gerhard, 1937-1953 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Stellmacher, Karl, 1956-1958 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Stenzel, Annie, 1936-1943 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Stenzel, Bertha, 1943-1952 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Stern, Antonie--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1925 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Stern, Otto, 1940-1944 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Sternberg, Wolfgang, 1941-1942 (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - Sternberg, Wolfgang, 1943-1944 (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - Sternberg, Wolfgang, 1945-1946 (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - Sternberg, Wolfgang, 1946-1947 (Box 84, Folder 18)
    - Sternberg, Wolfgang, 1948 (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - Sternberg, Wolfgang, 1949-1951 (Box 84, Folder 20)
    - Stevens Institute of Technology, 1948-1949, undated (Box 84, Folder 21)
    - Stiefel, E., 1947-1956 (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Still, Karl-Friedrich, 1947-1960 (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Stoddard, George, 1961-1963 (Box 84, Folder 24)
    - Stoke, Harold W., 1957-1959 (Box 84, Folder 25)
    - Stoker, J.J., 1962-1966 (Box 84, Folder 26)
    - Stoker, J.J.--60th Birthday Issue of Communications, 1965 (Box 84, Folder 27)
    - Stoker, J.J.--"Bending and Buckling of Elastic Plates", 1941 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Stoker, J.J.--"Bending and Buckling of Elastic Plates" (copy 2), 1941 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Stoker, J.J.--"Nonlinear Vibrations", circa 1942 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Stoker, J.J.--"Numerical Solution of Flood Prediction and River Regulation Problems", 1953 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Stratton, J.A., 1955-1956 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Strauss, Lewis, 1938-1959 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Strauss, Lewis, 1938-1959 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Strauss, Lewis, 1938-1959 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Strauss, Lewis, 1947-1968 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Strutt, M.J.O., 1946 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Study 169, 1945 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Summary of Areas of Expansion of the Institute, 1956 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Summary of lecture given at N.O.I. (The Bases and Scope of the Linearized Theory of Compressible Fluid Flow with Special Reference to Steady Supersonic Flow), 1949 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Summary Report on Conditions of Science in Germany, Aug. 1947 with N. Artin, 1947, 1958 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Summary of talk at (NYU) Development Office, 1953 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - SUNY Stony Brook, 1966 (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Supplementary Notes-- Methods of Mathematical Physics, 1952-1953 (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Supplementary Notes-- Methods of Mathematical Physics, 1952-1953 (Box 85, Folder 18)
    - Supplementary Notes-- Methods of Mathematical Physics, 1952-1953 (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - Symposium on Applications of Modern Numerical Methods, 1954 (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - Symposium on Recent Advances in Science--Physics and Applied Mathematics, 1954 (Box 85, Folder 21)
    - Symposium on Theory of Electromagnetic Waves--Morris Kline, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - (Proposed) Symposium on Traffic Flow, 1966 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Synge, J.L., 1938-1951 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Synge, J.L., 1946-1962 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Szasz, Otto, 1938-1940 (Box 86, Folder 5)